TECH / SKILLS

HTML **UX DESIGN** CSS **UI DESIGN BOOTSTRAP** WIRE-FRAMING **JAVASCRIPT** PROTOTYPING **JQUERY USER RESEARCH** REACT MOCK UPS **EXPRESS GRAPHIC DESIGN** NODE.JS PHOTOGRAPHY NEXT IS **IMAGE EDITING MONGODB** GIT/GITHUB WORDPRESS HEROKU

SOFTWARE

VS CODE PHOTOSHOP
BOOTSTRAP STUDIO LIGHTROOM
AXURE RP ILLUSTRATOR
MS OFFICE ADOBE XD

SOFT SKILLS

CRITICAL THINKING AUTHENTICITY

COMMUNICATION TIME MANAGEMENT

FAST LEARNER RELIABILITY

DETAIL ORIENTATED INDEPENDANT

PERSONAL

Birthday : 11 April 1994

Nationality : South African & Greek

Languages : English

CONTACT

Claremont, Cape Town

+27 84 413 5465

nikitabatlis@live.com

www.nikitabatlis.github.io/portfolio/

linkedin.com/in/nikitabatlis/

github.com/NikitaBatlis

NIKITA BATLIS

Web Developer | UX/UI Designer

PROFILE

I thrive on creative front-end challenges and enjoy implementing UI trends into my current projects. I have a particular interest in accessible UX design and believe the key to a product's long-term success is putting the user's experience first.

I spent 4 years working on yachts and in hospitality, before returning home to continue my education and transition to a career in Web Development and UX/UI design. Having completed my boot-camp and diploma, I am looking for a graduate/junior position within a strong team to further my industry knowledge.

Equipped with a conscientious work ethic - I am a reliable, proactive colleague with a keen eye for detail, and will never skip an opportunity to learn something new.

EDUCATION

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPMENT BOOTCAMP

HYPERIONDEV, CAPE TOWN

A full MERN stack web development course that taught me to build dynamic, data-driven web applications with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node.js, MongoDB, Express & React.

BRAND & MARKETING MANAGEMENT

VEGA SCHOOL, CAPE TOWN

Part time 6 month course to develop both theoretical and practical knowledge in the field of brand building and digital marketing.

PROFESSIONAL DIPLOMA IN UX DESIGN

UX DESIGN INSTITUTE, IRELAND

Correspondence 1 year diploma in professional UX design user theory, research methods, prototyping and wireframing work-flows, as well as design thinking and analysis.

2019 - 2020

CERTIFICATE IN COMMERCIAL PHOTOGRAPHY

VEGA SCHOOL, CAPE TOWN

Full time 2 year certification in professional photography, image editing and manipulation, as well as graphic design.

2013 - 2014

JOB HISTORY

Photographer & Worpress Designer

Freelance Student | Cape Town

Apr 2019 - Present

Nov 2018 - Mar 2019

Dec 2017 - Sep 2018

Commissioned portraiture, location and real estate photography. Visual branding and mock ups. As well as Wordpress website theme setup and graphic designs for small local start-ups.

Location Scout & Researcher

Cape Town Productions | www.ctprod.co.za | Cape Town

A summer contract managing and updating the company's location database while researching and scouting new locations around Cape Town. Along with assisting on set and in-office coordinators.

Stewardess

Katara | 123m Private Motor Yacht | Spain

Working & living closely with a team of 70 multinationals. Managing & maintaining luxury yacht interiors while delivering 10 Star service for Arab Royalty.

Junior Stewardess

Apr 2017 - Sep 2017

Lady Nag Nag | 53m Motor Yacht | France & Monaco

Seasonal contract on board a demanding, fast pased privately owned yacht.

REFERENCES UPON REQUEST